One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
Wealth, fame, power...
‫،الثروة والصيت والقوة‬
Gold Roger, the King of the Pirates, obtained everything the world has to offer.
‫الرجل الذي نال كل ما في هذا العالم، ملك القراصنة غولد روجر‬
What he said in his final moments drove countless souls to the seas.
‫أجَّج قوله قبيل موته اندفاع الناس إلى البحار‬
You want my treasure?
‫كنزي؟ إنه لكم إن أردتموه‬
People set their sights on the Grand Line in pursuit of their dreams.
‫شدّ الرجال رحالهم نحو الغراند لاين مطاردين أحلامهم‬
The world has truly entered the Great Pirate Era!
‫العالم الآن يعيش عصر القراصنة العظيم‬
Come aboard and bring along all your hopes and dreams
‫أحلامنا جمعناها فيما بيننا‬
I know together we'll find everything we're looking for Sagashi mono wo sagashi ni yuku no sa
‫قاصدين البحث عما نريد الحصول عليه‬
One Piece! ONE PIECE
‫ون ون بيس بيس‬
Compasses? Not for me. Left them all behind Rashinban nante juutai no moto
‫ما كانت البوصلة لتأتي لنا سوى بالتأخير‬
I'm headed out to sea, with my heart serving as guide Netsu ni ukasare kaji wo toru no sa
‫نمضي في طريقنا بهمة المشاعر المشتعلة‬
Following the ancient map to the spot marked "X" reveals Hokori kabutteta takara no chizu mo
‫وخريطة الكنز القديمة التي يعلوها التراب‬
Yeah, it's only legendary till someone proves it's real Tashikameta no nara densetsu janai!
‫لن تكون محض قصة خرافية إن تبينا صحتها‬
When the world's got you down,
‫وإن هبت بداخلك عواصف هوجاء‬
Their biorhythm will carry you through BIORHYTHM nokkatte
‫فتمايل على إيقاع الآخرين حولك‬
We're gonna make the most of it Omoi sugoseba ii!
‫وتجاهل وجودها‬
Come aboard and bring along all your hopes and dreams Arittake no yume wo kaki atsume
‫أحلامنا جمعناها فيما بيننا‬
I know together we'll find everything we're looking for Sagashi mono wo sagashi ni yuku no sa
‫قاصدين البحث عما نريد الحصول عليه‬
Got some change to my name, POCKET no COIN
‫عملة أحفظها في جيبي‬
and maybe you wanna be my friend? Soreto YOU WANNA BE MY FRIEND?
‫وهل تريد أن تكون صديقي؟‬
We are, we are on the cruise! WE ARE, WE ARE ON THE CRUISE!
‫،نحن نحن نخوض مغامرة‬
WE ARE!
‫نحن نحن‬
To the Sea
‫إلى البحر‬
H-He beat him...
‫!قد هزمه‬
H-He beat Captain Kuro!
‫!هـ-هزم القبطان كورو‬
Even the Marines were no match for Kuro of a Thousand Plans!
‫!الرجل الذي لم تستطع حتّى البحرية مضاهاته، كورو ذو المئة حيلة‬
But he really beat him!
‫!هزمه حقًّا‬
Just who are you?!
‫!من تكون؟‬
Monkey D. Luffy.
‫.مونكي دي لوفي‬
I'd never lose to a pirate who ditches his name and runs from the sea.
‫يستحيل أن أخسر ضد قرصان تخلّى عن اسمه وهرب من البحر‬
The only time a pirate should abandon his name is when he dies!
‫لا يتيعن على القرصان التخلي عن اسمه إلّا حال وفاته‬
Luffy?! Nope, doesn't ring a bell...
‫لوفي؟ لم أسمع به من قبل فعلًا‬
Remember my name for the rest of your lives!
‫تذكروا اسمي طالما حييتم‬
I'm the man who's gonna be King of the Pirates!
‫!فأنا الرجل الذي سيصير ملك القراصنة‬
This guy's...
‫...إنّه‬
Take him and go!
‫خذوه وغادروا‬
Never come back!
‫!لا تعودوا إلى هنا أبدًا‬
Run!
‫!اهربوا‬
You did good.
‫...أحسنت‬
Weigh anchor! Hurry!
‫!ارفعوا المرساة، بسرعة‬
I guess even you would collapse after all you've been through...
‫...حتّى أنت ستنهار بعد تلقيك لكل تلك الضربات‬
So...
‫،أخبرني‬
what were you mad about earlier?
‫ممّ كنت غاضبًا قبل قليل؟‬
I hate them.
‫.أنا أكرههم‬
They're wrong.
‫،إنّهم مخطئون‬
That's not how crewmates are supposed to act.
‫فلا ينبغي للرفاق التصرف هكذا‬
What're you talking about?
‫عمّ تتحدث؟‬
It's in their nature.
‫،هذا واضح‬
Pirates aren't exactly the merry bunch you make them out to be.
‫القراصنة ليسوا صالحين كما تظنّهم‬
I want some meat.
‫أريد أكل لحمًا‬
You're unbelievable!
‫...إنّك‬
Can you keep everything that's happened here a secret?
‫هل يمكنكم أن تبقوا كلّ ما حدث هنا سرًّا؟‬
What?! Keep it a secret?!
‫ماذا؟ سر؟‬
Why would we do that?!
‫لمَ قد نفعل هذا؟‬
Yeah! After we just fought for the sake of the village!
‫صحيح، قاتلنا من أجل القرية‬
I bet it'll change how everyone thinks of you!
‫سيغيّر الجميع رأيهم بك أيضًا‬
You'll be the village hero!
‫!ستصبح بطل القرية‬
– Yeah!
‫!صحيح‬
Usopp, you need to clear up this misunderstanding.
‫...أوسوب-سان... عليك أن توضّح سوء فهم الجميع‬
What misunderstanding?
‫هذا ليس سوء فهم، فقد نادوني بالمُبالغ كالعادة فحسب‬
Why go and scare everyone when it's been settled?
‫لا داعي لإثارة رعب الجميع بشيء قد انتهى سلفًا‬
This was a one-time thing.
‫،بغضّ النظر عن أحداث هذه المرة‬
No pirate's going out of their way to attack a remote village like this one again.
‫فلن يهاجم قراصنة قرية معزولة كهذه‬
I'm just going to pretend that nothing ever happened.
‫سأدّعي أنّه لم يحدث شيء‬
It was all a lie.
‫كان كلّه كذبة‬
But of course, I can't force you.
‫...لن أرغمكم، ولكن‬
No, we can do it!
‫لا، أستطيع فعلها‬
If it's for the good of the village!
‫إن كان ذلك من صالح القرية‬
I agree!
‫أنا أيضًا‬
Me too! I'll never say a word, ever!
‫أنا أيضًا، سأصمت إلى الأبد‬
Kaya...
‫...كايا‬
Will that be hard for you?
‫أسيكون الأمر صعبًا عليك؟‬
No.
‫.كلّا‬
Where could Usopp be this morning?
‫أتساءل ماذا حدث لأوسوب-كن؟‬
It just doesn't feel right... I can't get motivated.
‫لا أعلم ما بي اليوم‬
Mommy...
‫...ماما‬
Is Mr. Liar not coming today?
‫ألن يأتي الأخ الكذّاب اليوم؟‬
That lying runt...
‫...ذلك الطفل المُبالغ الوغد‬
Why is he so late?!
‫أين هو اليوم؟‬
You think maybe I was a bit too harsh yesterday?
‫أقسينا عليه كثيرًا الأمس؟‬
I'm sure he'll be back to his old tricks tomorrow!
‫...سيعود لعادته بحلول الغد‬
Just watch.
‫حتمًا...‬
Thanks!
‫شكرًا لكم‬
I wouldn't have been able to protect the village without you guys!
‫لم أكن لأحمي القرية لولا وجودكم‬
What're you talking about?
‫عمّ تتحدث؟‬
If it weren't for you, I wouldn't have done a thing!
‫لم أكن لأتحرك لو أنّك لم تفعل شيئًا‬
Me neither!
‫وأنا أيضًا‬
Who cares about that?
‫هذا لا يهم‬
I made a killing!
‫!فقد حصلت على كنز‬
Thanks to this incident,
‫ساعدتني هذه الحادثة على اتخاذ قرار‬
Captain Usopp! What was it you wanted to talk to us about?
‫ما الذي أردت التحدث عنه أيها القبطان أوسوب؟‬
You guys fought well against those Black Cat Pirates!
‫...أحسنتم بقتال قراصنة القط الأسود أولئك‬
As captain, I feel very proud!
‫أنا في غاية الفخر بكم بصفتي قبطانكم‬
We overcame our biggest and greatest battle since we formed
‫تغلبنا على أكبر وأعظم معركة منذ أن شكلنا‬
the Usopp Pirates five years ago, when you guys were just four years old!
‫!قراصنة أوسوب قبل خمس سنوات حين كنتم بعمر الرابعة فقط‬
– Yeah!
‫!أجل‬
So, I know this is sudden...
‫،ولذلك، أعلم أنّ هذا مفاجئ‬
but I've decided to set out to sea by myself!
‫لكنّي قررت الإبحار وحدي‬
I'm gonna be a real pirate!
‫!سأصير قرصانًا حقيقيًّا‬
I'd always been unsure of whether I should stay or go...
‫...كنت محتارًا دائمًا ما إن كنت أريد البقاء هنا إلى الأبد أم لا‬
But... when I met them, I finally made up my mind!
‫لكن حين رأيتهم، اتخذت قراري أخيرًا‬
I feel that as a man, I must set out onto the vast ocean!
‫أشعر أنّه بما أنّي رجل، فعليّ أن أُبحر في هذا البحر الواسع‬
So...
‫لذلك، سأغادر هذه القرية‬
The pirate flag is calling me!
‫:السبب واحد‬
What other reason do you need?!
‫!علم القراصنة يناديني‬
Captain! You're lying, right?!
‫ألست تكذب أيها القبطان؟‬
You're lying again, right?!
‫أليست هذه كذبة أيضًا؟‬
It's way too sudden!
‫من التسرع أن تفعل ذلك‬
Don't you love this village, Captain?!
‫ألا تحب هذه القرية أيّها القبطان؟‬
What'll happen to the Usopp Pirates?!
‫ماذا سيحلّ بقراصنة أوسوب؟‬
You've been good to me, guys...
‫سببتُ لكم كثيرًا من المتاعب‬
I plan to leave without telling the villagers.
‫أنوي المغادرة دون إخبار القرويين‬
Give them my regards.
‫أبلغوهم تحيّاتي‬
No...
‫...لا‬
I don't want to!
‫!لا أريد‬
Don't go, Captain!
‫!لا تذهب أيّها القبطان‬
Do you remember this place?
‫أتذكرون هذا المكان؟‬
This is where we first met.
‫إنّه المكان الذي التقينا فيه أول مرة‬
All done!
‫!انتهيت‬
Mr. Liar!
‫أيّها الأخ الكذاب‬
Who are you guys?! Don't act all buddy-buddy with me!
‫من أنتم؟ ما هذا التودّد؟‬
But you're famous!
‫لأنّك مشهور‬
Yeah, you're like a celebrity...
‫...أجل، إنّك مشهور‬
I see!
‫!فهمت‬
Finally some respect! So, people are now calling me Captain Usopp!
‫بدأ الناس بمناداتي القبطان أوسوب بكل احترام إذًا‬
Everyone calls you Usopp the Liar!
‫يناديك الجميع بالكذاب أوسوب‬
Alright! From this day forth, you're members of the Usopp Pirates too!
‫!حسنٌ، أنتم أعضاء في طاقم قراصنة أوسوب بدءًا من اليوم‬
– What?
‫ماذا؟‬
Don't "what" me!
‫!لا تقولوا هذا‬
A lot's happened, huh?
‫ألم يحدث الكثير؟‬
It's Cerberus!
‫!سيربيروس! طاردوه‬
A dragon!
‫!تنين! اقبضوا عليه‬
Flour Star!
‫!نجمة الدقيق‬
You're amazing, Captain!
‫إنّك مذهل يا قبطان‬
But of course!
‫!بالطبع! فأنا محارب بحر شجاع‬
We don't wanna hear about the good old days!
‫لا نريد سماع هذه الذكريات‬
Yeah! We don't wanna hear about that!
‫!صحيح، لا نريد سماعها‬
This isn't like you, Captain!
‫!هذا ليس من شيمك أيّها القبطان‬
Why are you saying this stuff now?!
‫لماذا تقول هذه الأشياء الآن؟‬
It's almost like you're...
‫...وكأنّك‬
You're so stupid, Captain!
‫!إنّك أحمق أيّها القبطان‬
Stupid!
‫!أحمق‬
What are your ambitions in life?!
‫ما طموحكم؟‬
To run a pub!
‫أن أدير حانة‬
To be a master carpenter!
‫أن أصبح نجّارًا محترفًا‬
To be a novelist!
‫أن أصبح كاتب روايات‬
Then swear right here that you'll continue on each of your paths...
‫إ-إذًا أقسموا هنا أنّكم ستستمرون بدروبكم جميعًا‬
and never let the fires of your ambitions go out!
‫!وأنّكم لن تسمحوا لنيران طموحاتكم أن تخمد‬
As of today...
‫...اعتبارًا من اليوم‬
the Usopp Pirates...
‫...فإنّ مجموعة قراصنة أوسوب‬
are disbanded!
‫!حُلّت‬
Well, we've eaten. We should get going now.
‫تناولنا الطعام، علينا الذهاب الآن‬
Yeah...
‫معك حق‬
There you are!
‫كنتم هنا إذًا‬
Hey, miss!
‫أهلًا يا آنسة‬
You're out of bed already?
‫أبوسعك النهوض من فراشك؟‬
Yes...
‫أجل‬
My illness this past year was due to the grief from losing my parents.
‫مرضي خلال السنة الماضية‬
Usopp's been there to cheer me up, but...
‫وأبهجني أوسوب-سان كثيرًا أيضًا‬
I can't stay coddled forever!
‫لا ينبغي لي أن أُدلّل طوال الوقت‬
I've prepared a little something for you as a token of my gratitude!
‫أعددت هدية لكم جميعًا أهديها لكم من أعماق قلبي‬
Please accept it!
‫أرجوكم اقبلوها‬
All packed...
‫انتهيت من حزم أغراضي‬
Guess it's farewell to this house, too!
‫إنّه الوداع لهذا المنزل أيضًا‬
What?!
‫ماذا؟‬
What the...? I can't get out!
‫يا لهذه المصيبة... لا أستطيع الخروج‬
Damn it!
‫!سحقًا‬
A caravel!
‫!كارفيل‬
Can we really have this?!
‫أيمكننا الحصول عليها حقًّا؟‬
Yes, it's all yours!
‫أجل، استخدموها رجاءً‬
It's a slightly older model, but I designed it myself!
‫إنّها قديمة قليلًا ولكنّي صممتها بنفسي‬
A carvel-built caravel, with lateen sails and a central stern rudder...
‫سفينة شراعيّة مصنوعة على طريقة كارفيل‬
the Going Merry!
‫!إنها غوينغ ميري‬
Let me explain the running rigging!
‫دعني أشرح لك طريقة عمل حبال الأشرعة‬
First, about the clew-garnet yard adjustment–
‫...أوّلًا، بشأن ضبط ياردات شبكة كروغر‬
No, no!
‫!لا، لا! اشرح السفينة لي‬
What a nice ship!
‫يا لروعتها من سفينة‬
Especially the front—it's so cool!
‫!لاسيّما مقدمتها، إنّها رائعة‬
We've loaded it with everything we thought you might need on your voyage.
‫ملأناها بكلّ شيء قد تحتاجونه في رحلتكم‬
Thanks! It leaves everything to be desired!
‫!شكرًا لك، إنّها مثلى‬
It's "nothing to be desired," you idiot.
‫.بل عليك أن تقول «مثاليّة» أيّها الغبي‬
Stop this thing!
‫أوقفوا هذا الشيء‬
Usopp!
‫!أوسوب-سان‬
What's he doing?
‫ماذا يفعل؟‬
Let's just stop him.
‫لنوقفه على أيّ حال‬
He's about to collide with the ship.
‫سيصطدم مباشرة بالسفينة على هذا الحال‬
Th-Thanks...
‫...شـ-شكرًا لكما‬
Yeah.
‫لا بأس‬
So... you're really going out to sea, Usopp?
‫.ستخوض غمار البحر حقًّا إذًا يا أوسوب-سان‬
Yeah.
‫أجل، قررت أن أذهب قبل أن أبدأ بتغيير رأيي‬
Don't stop me now.
‫لا توقفيني‬
I won't.
‫لن أفعل‬
I could just tell somehow.
‫توقعت ذلك‬
That's kind of sad, too!
‫لكن هذا يحزنني قليلًا‬
The next time I come to this village,
‫،حين أزور هذه القرية في المرة القادمة‬
my stories will sound more unbelievable than any tall tale!
‫فسأخبرك عن قصص مغامرات تبدو كالكذب أكثر من الكذب نفسه‬
Okay! I look forward to it!
‫!أجل، أتطلع لها‬
You guys take care, too!
‫!وأنتم اعتنوا بأنفسكم! فلنلتق في مكانٍ ثانيةً‬
How come?
‫لماذا؟‬
Huh? "How come?"
‫ماذا؟ لماذا؟‬
Man, would it kill you to play nice?
‫...إنّك غير اجتماعي حقًّا‬
I'm gonna be a pirate too, so we'll meet on the high seas eventually!
‫!سأصير قرصانًا مثلكم، لذا سنتقابل في البحر يومًا‬
What're you talking about?
‫عمّ تتحدث؟‬
Get on already.
‫اركب بسرعة‬
You're one of us now, aren't you?
‫ألسنا رفاقًا الآن؟‬
I-I...
‫...ا-القبطان‬
I get to be captain, right?!
‫ألستُ أنا القبطان؟‬
Don't be dumb!
‫!لا تتحامق، أنا القبطان‬
There goes the captain...
‫...ذهب القبطان‬
Yeah.
‫أجل‬
But he's with those guys, so I feel less worried now.
‫ولكن بما أنّه معهم فقد ارتحت قليلًا‬
Yeah.
‫صحيح. لم أرَ أقوياء مثلهم‬
It makes sense though.
‫ما باليد حيلة‬
He always said he wanted to be a pirate.
‫طالما كان يقول إنّه يريد أن يصبح قرصانًا‬
The villagers won't be happy to hear it, though...
‫سيحزن القرويون حين نخبرهم عن هذا‬
It's all so sudden... He's the reason this place was so lively.
‫هذا مفاجئ، لقد كان يُبهج الأجواء وحده‬
I just had an idea!
‫!لديّ فكرة‬
– What is it?
‫ماذا؟‬
Merry...
‫...ميري‬
Yes?
‫نعم؟‬
Lying is painful...
‫...الكذب يؤلم‬
Are you referring to Klahadore?
‫أتعنين كلاهادور؟‬
No...
‫...لا‬
You mean how you actually wanted to stop Usopp from going?
‫أتعنين كيف أنّك أردتِ منع أوسوب-كن من الذهاب حقًّا؟‬
Miss...
‫يا آنستي، أخبرني القرويون قصة عن طفولته ذات مرة‬
Shortly after Usopp's father ran off from the village,
‫،بعد وقت قصير من مغادرة والد أوسوب لهذه القرية‬
his mother passed away.
‫.فقد والدته‬
The pirates are coming!
‫!أتى القراصنة‬
Dad's pirate ship is here!
‫!قراصنة أبي هنا‬
H-Hold on, Usopp!
‫!تـ-توقف يا أوسوب! لا ينبغي لك أن تصرخ‬
Dad came to pick us up!
‫عاد أبي لنا‬
D-Don't be silly... Usopp...
‫...لـ-لا تكن سخيفًا يا أوسوب‬
But he said he'd take us with him when you get better, Mom!
‫!ولكنّه قال إنّه سيأخذنا معه للمغامرة حين تتحسنين يا أمّي‬
Your father won't be coming back...
‫...لن يعود والدك‬
But... I'm proud to have married him...
‫ولكنّي فخورة لتزوّجي منه‬
There's a miracle cure out there!
‫!هناك دواء أسطوري يمكنه شفاء أيّ مرض‬
You're so silly...
‫...يا لسخافتك... إنك تحلم كثيرًا‬
I don't care if I'm silly!
‫!لا بأس بكوني سخيفًا، أنا أحلم فعلًا‬
I'm the son of a pirate!
‫!وأنا ابن قرصان‬
Grow up to be a brave man like your father...
‫...اكبر لتصير رجلًا شجاعًا مثل والدك‬
The pirates are coming!
‫!أتى القراصنة‬
Perhaps out of loneliness,
‫،ربّما بسبب وحدته‬
he continued to shout it out after she passed.
‫استمر بتلك الصرخات بعد وفاة والدته‬
All in the hopes that his father's pirate ship would one day be at the shore...
‫،آملًا أن تأتي سفينة قراصنة والده يومًا إلى الساحل‬
that one day, he would come back for him.
‫آملًا أن يأتي له يومًا‬
The villagers say that lie of his also contains his wish.
‫يقول القرويون إنّ كذبته تلك تحمل أمنية أيضًا‬
Pirates!
‫!قراصنة‬
As someone who lost his own parents in this village,
‫،بصفته فتًى خسر والديه في هذه القرية‬
it's no wonder he couldn't ignore you when you lost yours.
‫فإنّه لم يتمكن من تركك وحيدة بما أنّه حدث نفس الشيء لك‬
You will need to grow stronger now, too!
‫عليكِ أن تصيري أقوى‬
To live up to everything he's done until today!
‫استجابةً لكلّ ما فعله حتّى اليوم‬
Yes!
‫!أجل‬
To our new ship and crewmate!
‫،بمناسبة السفينة الجديدة ورفيقنا الجديد‬
– Cheers!
‫!نخبكم‬
They said they weren't gonna die, that they would fight to live.
‫قالوا إنّهم يقاتلون للعيش وليس للموت‬
Usopp's lies always spoke about the joy of living.
‫طالما كانت تتحدث أكاذيب أوسوب عن متعة العيش‬
They cheered me up and told me to live!
‫كانت تبهجني وتخبرني أن أعيش‬
Indeed.
‫معكِ حق‬
Here we go!
‫!لننطلق‬
Are we really gonna do this?!
‫أسنفعلها حقًّا؟‬
You bet! We're following in our captain's footsteps!
‫!سنفعلها، سنسير على أثر القبطان‬
– The pirates are comiiing!
‫!أتى القراصنة‬
You know what, Merry?
‫أوَتعلم يا ميري؟‬
I'm going to be a doctor!
‫!سأصير طبيبة‬
What a wonderful ambition!
‫!يا لعظمته من هدف‬
As a kid, I had a dream of a dazzling treasure
‫،عِندما كُنتُ طفلاً صغيرًا‬
I had a map in my head that I knew would lead me
‫كانت لديَّ رؤيا عن خريطة كنز‬
Charted a course all on my own, so nobody would beat me
‫ولطالما بحثت عن ذلك المكان العجيب‬
The promised land was in my hand, drew a line in the sand
‫قبل أن يهزمني شخصٌ ما ويسبقني إليه‬
My one ambition's slipping right through my hands
‫إذا كانَ العالم سيتغيّر‬
But if the world ever changes I'll call out your name
‫قبل أن أتمكن من تحقيق حُلمي‬
We could return to a time when our lives were still the same
‫في تلك الحال ارجع بالزمن للوقت الذي لم أعلم به عن شيء‬
Take me to the place where memories remain
‫حتّى لا تتلاشى ذكرياتي‬